const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 30-year-old male presents to the outpatient department with complaints of loss of pain and temperature sensations in the right arm. He has a history of gunshot wounds to the left side of the spinal cord. Where is the lesion located?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior spinocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral corticospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Medial lemniscus","bool":false},{"option":"Left lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":true}]},{"id":1,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"An 81-year-old female comes to the neurology outpatient department with complaints of diminished facial expression (often termed masked facies), stooped posture, slowing of voluntary movement, taking progressively shortened, accelerated steps, rigidity, and a “pill-rolling” tremor. The first gene to be identified as a cause of Parkinson's Disease encodes a-synuclein, an abundant lipid-binding protein normally associated with synapses. Mutations in alpha-synuclein take the form of point mutations and amplification of the region of chromosome 4q21 that contains the gene. What is the mode of inheritance of these genes?","answers":[{"option":"Mitochondrial inheritance","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal recessive","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal dominant","bool":true},{"option":"X-linked dominant","bool":false},{"option":"X-linked recessive","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following anti-depressants has a stronger risk of self-harm and suicide?","answers":[{"option":"Tricyclic antidepressants","bool":true},{"option":"Selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors","bool":false},{"option":"Atypical antidepressants","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin norepinephrine reuptake inhibitors","bool":false},{"option":"Monoamine oxidase inhibitors","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following is a common variable used for a pie chart?","answers":[{"option":"Weight","bool":false},{"option":"Length","bool":false},{"option":"Gender","bool":true},{"option":"Height","bool":false},{"option":"Age","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 40-year-old female presents with right-sided unilateral headaches for the past 5 months. Physical examination yields no remarkable findings. The representative gross appearance of the lesion seen on the CT scan of the head shows a dura-based mass. Surgical removal and microscopic examination show elongated cells with pale, oblong nuclei and pink cytoplasm with occasional psammoma bodies. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Metastasis","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytoma","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculoma","bool":false},{"option":"Ependymoma","bool":false},{"option":"Meningioma","bool":true}]},{"id":5,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following options include all four cardinal symptoms that are present in Parkinson disease?","answers":[{"option":"Tremor, bradycardia, rigidity, and postural instability","bool":false},{"option":"Ageusia, bradykinesia, dementia, and rigidity","bool":false},{"option":"Tremor, bradykinesia, rigidity, and postural instability","bool":true},{"option":"Tremor, bradykinesia, rigidity, and depression","bool":false},{"option":"Tremor, bradykinesia, seborrhea, and constipation","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 66-year-old male complains of progressive problems with gait, speech, and hand tremors for two years. He also has occasional lightheadedness with standing and a 6-year history of impotence. He has no past medical history and takes no medications. His blood pressure is 140/84 mm Hg lying down, and 98/72 mm Hg standing, without change in pulse. Mental status is normal. He has reduced facial expression, high-pitched dysarthria, and mild anterocollis. There is no resting tremor. He has an irregular tremulousness of both hands when outstretched, worse on the right, without ataxia on finger-to-nose testing. He is bradykinetic and his gait is slow, shuffling, and unsteady. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Corticobasal degeneration","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple system atrophy-cerebellar subtype","bool":false},{"option":"Progressive supranuclear palsy","bool":false},{"option":"Parkinson's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple system atrophy-parkinsonian subtype","bool":true}]},{"id":7,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Compared to sporadic Parkinson disease (PD), PD that is due to a dominantly inherited mutation in the a-synuclein gene is characterized by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Less frequent cognitive decline","bool":false},{"option":"More cortical features (such as aphasia)","bool":true},{"option":"Older age at the onset of symptoms","bool":false},{"option":"The stronger association with neuromuscular junction dysfunction","bool":false},{"option":"More robust response to dopaminergic therapy","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following is the most common brain tumor in children occurring in the posterior cranial fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Astrocytoma","bool":false},{"option":"Hemangioblastoma","bool":false},{"option":"Medulloblastoma","bool":true},{"option":"Central neurocytoma","bool":false},{"option":"Ependymoma","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following is considered a subset of a population?","answers":[{"option":"Subjects","bool":false},{"option":"Target population","bool":false},{"option":"Subunit","bool":false},{"option":"Participants","bool":false},{"option":"Sample","bool":true}]},{"id":10,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"How soon after a stroke should rehabilitation be initiated?","answers":[{"option":"Immediately","bool":true},{"option":"6 hours","bool":false},{"option":"30 minutes","bool":false},{"option":"2 hours","bool":false},{"option":"1 day","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the disease-modifying medications used for multiple sclerosis (MS) is administered via the intramuscular route?","answers":[{"option":"Teriflunomide","bool":false},{"option":"Dimethyl fumarate","bool":false},{"option":"Fingolimod","bool":false},{"option":"Glatiramer acetate","bool":false},{"option":"Interferon-beta","bool":true}]},{"id":12,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A politician intends to implement a primary prevention program against neurological diseases in the area. Which of the following measures would be appropriate as a primary prevention in the community?","answers":[{"option":"Screening of psychiatric diseases","bool":false},{"option":"Fostering strong social support","bool":true},{"option":"Preparing expert neurosurgeons","bool":false},{"option":"Building advance hospitals","bool":false},{"option":"Free supplies of psychiatric drugs","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A group of students used an analysis of variance test (ANOVA) to test the hypothesis that the mean systolic blood pressure among various ethnicities is different. In the first step of ANOVA, they obtained an F-statistic less than the critical value.  What would be the second step considering their analysis is correct?","answers":[{"option":"Report the results as it is","bool":false},{"option":"Do the post hoc analysis","bool":false},{"option":"Reject the null hypothesis (H°)","bool":false},{"option":"Apply more advanced statistical tests","bool":true},{"option":"Re-do the analysis","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A student compares the body weights of a group of 100 children before and after four weeks of nutrition supplementation for his research project. His hypothesis is: \"the nutrition supplementation brings a change in the body weights of children\". He uses an independent sample t-test for his hypothesis testing and finds highly significant results at a p-value of 0.001. His professor checks his report and rejects it. Which of the following assumptions must have been violated?","answers":[{"option":"Independence of observations should be there","bool":true},{"option":"Independent variable should consist of three categories","bool":false},{"option":"The dependent variable should be categorical","bool":false},{"option":"There should be more significant outliers","bool":false},{"option":"The dependent variable should be skewed","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A lecturer is teaching epidemiological study designs to his students. He emphasizes the follow-up data of the patients and how to reduce the loss of follow-up in an observational study design. The professor is teaching which of the following epidemiological study designs to his students?","answers":[{"option":"Case series","bool":false},{"option":"Experimental study","bool":false},{"option":"Case control study","bool":false},{"option":"Cross-sectional study","bool":false},{"option":"Cohort study","bool":true}]},{"id":16,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A group of students was conducting a research study to find out the risk factors of stomach cancer in Karachi city. They had a limited budget and time to complete this study on a rare disease such as stomach cancer. Which of the following epidemiological study designs would be appropriate to fulfill their study objectives?","answers":[{"option":"Cross-sectional study","bool":false},{"option":"Case control study","bool":true},{"option":"Experimental study","bool":false},{"option":"Case series","bool":false},{"option":"Cohort study","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A group of researchers was conducting a study on the relationship of high dose vitamin D on stomach cancer 5-year survival outcome. They identified 100 stomach cancer patients and randomly allocated 50 patients to vitamin D and the other 50 to the placebo through a coin toss. The above statement refers to which of the following study designs?","answers":[{"option":"Case control study","bool":false},{"option":"Cross-sectional study","bool":false},{"option":"Experimental study","bool":true},{"option":"Case series","bool":false},{"option":"Cohort study","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"While working in the health office of district Thatta a student came across several cases of oral cancers from 10 talukas. The student also had data on the number of gutka outlets in different talukas. He wanted to find an association between the number of persons affected and gutka sales in the area. What would be the most appropriate study design?","answers":[{"option":"Correlational","bool":true},{"option":"Cross-sectional","bool":false},{"option":"Case series","bool":false},{"option":"Cohort","bool":false},{"option":"Case control","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A medical student wants to find the prevalence of coronary heart disease among adult males in the district central of Karachi. Which epidemiological study design is most appropriate for this study?","answers":[{"option":"Clinical trial","bool":false},{"option":"Cross sectional","bool":true},{"option":"Cohort","bool":false},{"option":"Case control","bool":false},{"option":"Case series","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Qualitative data does not have quantitative x and y observations for each participant so the relationship between two variables cannot be computed by correlation coefficient. For example: the frequency of males smoking versus females smoking. Which one of the following tests can be performed to see the association between two variables in such situations?","answers":[{"option":"Chi square test","bool":true},{"option":"Analysis of variance (ANOVA)","bool":false},{"option":"Correlation","bool":false},{"option":"Paired T-test","bool":false},{"option":"Independent T-test","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A survey of 100 men and 100 women revealed that 15 of the men and 36 of the women were overweight. The chi-square test of significance was applied to find an association at alpha equal to 0.05. Which one of the following options contains the correct decision if the calculated value for Chi is greater than the Chi critical?","answers":[{"option":"Inconclusive","bool":false},{"option":"Fail to accept the alternate hypothesis","bool":false},{"option":"Accept the null hypothesis","bool":false},{"option":"Reject the null hypothesis","bool":true},{"option":"Reject the alternate hypothesis","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following steps should be avoided while giving first aid to the victim of a snake bite?","answers":[{"option":"Incision or suction of venom from bitten area","bool":true},{"option":"Application of local antibiotic","bool":false},{"option":"Immobilizing the person","bool":false},{"option":"Removing any items or clothing which may constrict the bitten area","bool":false},{"option":"Cleaning the wound area with water","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"The snake venom can cause damage to multiple systems of the body depending upon the type of snake venom injected by the snake bite. A bite may also trigger a potentially fatal anaphylactic reaction. The manifestations of local pain, redness, swelling, and extravasation of blood are mostly in envenomation by which of the following snakes?","answers":[{"option":"Rattlesnake","bool":false},{"option":"Krait","bool":false},{"option":"Sea snake","bool":false},{"option":"Pit viper","bool":true},{"option":"Cobra","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A consultant asked a medical student to assess a patient on a Glasgow coma scale in the emergency department. This scale generally assesses which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Gastrointestinal system","bool":false},{"option":"Neuromuscular system","bool":true},{"option":"Renal system","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiovascular system","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory system","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 60-year-old male patient was diagnosed as a case of Parkinson's disease in the neurology outpatient department. The neurophysician suggested levodopa for his disease-related symptoms. Which of the following statements is true about the mechanism of action of levodopa?","answers":[{"option":"Levodopa causes seizures","bool":false},{"option":"Levodopa is metabolized in liver","bool":false},{"option":"Levodopa is converted into dopamine by dopa decarboxylase in the brain","bool":true},{"option":"Levodopa is hydroxylated into the chemical compound in the brain","bool":false},{"option":"Levodopa is directly converted into dopamine in the periphery","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following statements is the most accurate regarding the drugs used for the treatment of Parkinson disease?","answers":[{"option":"The benefit of antimuscarinic drugs in Parkinson's disease is to relieve bradykinesia","bool":false},{"option":"Levodopa causes mydriasis and may precipitate an acute attack of glaucoma","bool":true},{"option":"Therapeutic effects of amantadine continue for several years","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine receptor agonists should never be used in Parkinson's disease before the trial of levodopa","bool":false},{"option":"Selegiline is a selective COMT inhibitor (catechol-o-methyl transferase inhibitor)","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following is a troublesome adverse effect of levodopa when used for Parkinson disease?","answers":[{"option":"Ototoxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Choreoathetosis of face & distal extremities","bool":true},{"option":"Seizures","bool":false},{"option":"Day time sedation","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A male patient reported to the psychiatric clinic for his psychiatric problem. He was prescribed lithium for his mental issues. Which of the following is the most accurate for the clinical indication of lithium?","answers":[{"option":"Acute mania","bool":true},{"option":"Tremors","bool":false},{"option":"Tardive dyskinesia","bool":false},{"option":"Rigidity","bool":false},{"option":"Choreoathetosis","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Haloperidol is not a suitable option for the treatment of which of the following psychiatric conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Amenorrhea-galactorrhea syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Acute mania","bool":false},{"option":"Resting tremors","bool":false},{"option":"Schizophrenia","bool":false},{"option":"Bipolar affective disorder","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 30-year-old male office worker suffers from intense migraine headaches. Which of the following drugs is a serotonin 5-HT (1D/1B) agonist useful for decreasing an acute migraine headache?","answers":[{"option":"Ondansetron","bool":false},{"option":"Cimetidine","bool":false},{"option":"Sumatriptan","bool":true},{"option":"Nitroprusside","bool":false},{"option":"Ergotamine","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 51-year-old woman presents with symptoms of major depression and closed-angle glaucoma. Which of the following antidepressants needs to be avoided in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Amitriptyline","bool":true},{"option":"Mirtazapine","bool":false},{"option":"Selegiline","bool":false},{"option":"Fluoxetine","bool":false},{"option":"Bupropion","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 23-year-old patient with a history of severe postoperative nausea and vomiting comes for plastic surgery. Which of the following anesthetic drugs would be best to use for maintenance in this situation?","answers":[{"option":"Halothane","bool":false},{"option":"Nitrous oxide","bool":false},{"option":"Propofol","bool":true},{"option":"Isoflurane","bool":false},{"option":"Sevoflurane","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 33-year-old female patient needs to be anesthetized before dilation and curettage for abnormal uterine bleeding. Her anesthesia is induced initially with an inhaled nonflammable anesthetic that contains no halogenated carbons. Which of the following agents best fits this description?","answers":[{"option":"Diethyl ether","bool":false},{"option":"Halothane","bool":false},{"option":"Nitrous oxide","bool":true},{"option":"Enflurane","bool":false},{"option":"Propofol","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 19-year-old man has a 4-cm laceration of the palmar aspect of his hand. The wound needs to be sutured with absorbable sutures. Before beginning the procedure, the wound is injected with lidocaine containing 1:100,000 parts epinephrine. The rationale behind the use of epinephrine is which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Slow anesthetic metabolism from tissue","bool":true},{"option":"Releases nitric oxide from the vessels","bool":false},{"option":"Increase bleeding to improve toxin release from the wound","bool":false},{"option":"Augment pain sensation","bool":false},{"option":"Vasodilation at the side of administration","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 7-year-old female is diagnosed with absence seizures by a neurophysician. Which of the following drugs will be most appropriate to prescribe as a drug of first choice for treating her seizures?","answers":[{"option":"Phenobarbital","bool":false},{"option":"Carbamazepine","bool":false},{"option":"Diazepam","bool":false},{"option":"Ethosuximide","bool":true},{"option":"Phenytoin","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following is a very potent and short-acting benzodiazepine when used as a hypnotic causes psychiatric disturbances in some cases?","answers":[{"option":"Tremazepam","bool":false},{"option":"Diazepam","bool":false},{"option":"Flurazepam","bool":false},{"option":"Triazolam","bool":true},{"option":"Nitrazepam","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Coadministration of monoamine oxidase inhibitors (MAOIs) with which one of the following drugs may induce a central serotonin syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Citalopram","bool":true},{"option":"Amitriptyline","bool":false},{"option":"Venlafaxine","bool":false},{"option":"Duloxetine","bool":false},{"option":"Bupropion","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following monoamine oxidase inhibitors (MAOIs) is most likely to produce a cheese reaction?","answers":[{"option":"Selegiline","bool":false},{"option":"Tranylcypromine","bool":true},{"option":"Mirtazapine","bool":false},{"option":"Clorgyline","bool":false},{"option":"Moclobemide","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following antidepressant drugs affect dopamine reuptake?","answers":[{"option":"Fluoxetine","bool":false},{"option":"Selegiline","bool":false},{"option":"Mirtazapine","bool":false},{"option":"Imipramine","bool":false},{"option":"Bupropion","bool":true}]},{"id":40,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A first-year anesthesiology resident reaches for isoflurane as the induction agent for a patient who is about to receive general anesthesia. When the attending faculty sees this, he quickly takes the syringe away from the resident because this agent can cause which of the following effects when used for induction?","answers":[{"option":"Coughing","bool":true},{"option":"Laryngeal relaxation","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Muscle relaxation","bool":false},{"option":"Dry mouth","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 70-year-old patient in the intensive care unit needs sedation due to prolonged endotracheal intubation. Which of the following medications should be avoided for sedation in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Propofol","bool":false},{"option":"Etomidate","bool":true},{"option":"Fentanyl","bool":false},{"option":"Dexmedetomidine","bool":false},{"option":"Ketamine","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 35-year-old male patient presents with appendicitis and requires a surgical intervention. He has a family history of malignant hyperthermia. Which anesthetic agent is the most appropriate to use in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Isoflurane","bool":false},{"option":"Desflurane","bool":false},{"option":"Sevoflurane","bool":false},{"option":"Succinylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Propofol","bool":true}]},{"id":43,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 78-year-old male patient with a long history of seizure disorder controlled with phenytoin presents to his dentist for routine follow-up. Which of the following findings must the dentist be concerned about and evaluate for?","answers":[{"option":"Jaw bone exposure","bool":false},{"option":"Exposed nerve roots","bool":false},{"option":"Dental caries","bool":false},{"option":"Gingival overgrowth","bool":true},{"option":"Teeth erosion","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A case of morphine poisoning is diagnosed in the medical emergency department. Which of the following drugs shall be given to reverse morphine intoxication in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Naloxone","bool":true},{"option":"Diazepam","bool":false},{"option":"Halothane","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Phenytoin sodium","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A young male patient suffers from a seizure disorder characterized by tonic rigidity of the extremities followed by 15 to 30 seconds of tremor progressing to massive jerking of the body. This clonic phase lasts for 1 to 2 minutes, leaving the patient in a stuporous state. Which of the following drugs would be most suitable for the long-term management of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Felbamate","bool":false},{"option":"Clonazepam","bool":false},{"option":"Ethosuximide","bool":false},{"option":"Phenytoin","bool":true},{"option":"Pregabalin","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 2-month-old male child presents with a history of progressively enlarging head size since birth. His fontanelles are bulging and tense. Which of the following is true regarding the production of CSF?","answers":[{"option":"Normally turnover of cerebrospinal fluid is 72 times a day","bool":false},{"option":"It is absorbed by the arachnoid granulation","bool":true},{"option":"The normal rate of production is 50 milliliters per hour","bool":false},{"option":"It is produced by the dura mater","bool":false},{"option":"A major source of production of cerebrospinal fluid is the ependymal lining","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 38-year-old male presented with complaints of intermittent headaches and drop attacks. Investigation reveals a colloid cyst in the ventricles causing hydrocephalus. This type of hydrocephalus is known as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Obstructive hydrocephalus","bool":true},{"option":"Communicating hydrocephalus","bool":false},{"option":"Colloid hydrocephalus","bool":false},{"option":"Arrested hydrocephalus","bool":false},{"option":"Normal pressure hydrocephalus","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 45-year-old male presents in the emergency room after a road traffic accident with complaints of vomiting and headache. Glasgow coma scale (GCS) shows M6 E4 V4. Pupils are anisocoric and reactive. A computed tomography (CT) scan reveals a biconvex hyperdensity over the right temporoparietal region along with a fracture of the temporal bone. The sensory level is at the umbilicus. What is the most likely source of blood?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior petrosal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Middle meningeal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Superior saggital sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Bridging veins","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 50-year-old male presents in the emergency room after a road traffic accident with an altered level of consciousness and vomiting. The patient has abnormal flexion in pain and opens his eyes in pain with no verbal response. Pupils are equal and reactive. A computed tomography (CT) scan reveals a crescent hyperdensity over the right frontoparietal region along with a midline shift. What is the total Glasgow coma scale (GCS) score of the patient?","answers":[{"option":"3","bool":false},{"option":"6","bool":true},{"option":"4","bool":false},{"option":"7","bool":false},{"option":"5","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 60-year-old male presents with a history of a fall, complaining of neck pain and difficulty in doing normal house activities. On examination, he has weakness and sensory disturbance more in the upper limbs than in the lower limbs. What kind of spinal cord injury does he have?","answers":[{"option":"Brown sequard injury","bool":false},{"option":"Complete cord injury","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinal cord syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior spinal cord syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Central cord injury","bool":true}]},{"id":51,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A young soldier on the field had a gunshot injury on his back. On examination, he had paralysis of the right leg, loss of proprioception and fine discrimination of the right leg, and loss of pain and temperature in the left leg. What kind of spinal cord injury he had?","answers":[{"option":"Central cord injury","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior spinal cord syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Complete cord injury","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinal cord syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Brown-sequard injury","bool":true}]},{"id":52,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 30-year-old male presents to the emergency room with sustained head trauma after which he developed a headache and bleeding from his right ear. A computed tomography (CT) scan shows a right temporal bone fracture. He is managed and discharged home after a period of observation. One week later he comes with difficulty in closing his right eye. Which of the following nerves is most likely to be involved?","answers":[{"option":"VII","bool":true},{"option":"VIII","bool":false},{"option":"V","bool":false},{"option":"VI","bool":false},{"option":"III","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 27-year-old nurse presented with occupational dysfunction and loss of interest in her hobbies for 2 months. She was convinced that she would not be able to work again nor would pursue her hobbies of trekking and painting. Recently, she broke up a relationship with her husband. She thought that her life was not worth living and had consumed 60 tablets of phenobarbitone to end her life. She is most likely suffering from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Post-traumatic stress disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Acute stress disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Depressive disorder","bool":true},{"option":"Conversion disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Adjustment disorder","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 26-year-old female is brought to the emergency department with symptoms of aggression, over-talkativeness, hyperactivity, and decreased sleep for one week. Her family reveals that she has had two similar episodes in the past 3 years, for which she received treatment. A diagnosis of bipolar affective disorder with a current episode of mania was made. Which of the following groups of medications would be suitable for treatment in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Mood stabilizers only","bool":false},{"option":"Mood stabilizers and antipsychotics","bool":true},{"option":"Antipsychotics only","bool":false},{"option":"Mood stabilizers and benzodiazepine","bool":false},{"option":"Antidepressants and antipsychotics","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 35-year-old female patient presents with complaints of restlessness, sweating, tachycardia, and difficulty in breathing for 1 month. These symptoms are episodic. There is a family history of hypertension. Laboratory investigation shows a normal level of vanillylmandelic acid (VMA) in urine. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Phobic anxiety disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperthyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Pheochromocytoma","bool":false},{"option":"Panic disorder","bool":true},{"option":"Generalized anxiety disorder","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 25-year-old woman suffers from insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus. She has been thoroughly informed on how to use insulin and what her diet should be. Furthermore, she is an intelligent girl who understands all of this. Nonetheless, at times, she secretly stops her insulin for no clear external gain like missing a test, and takes in too many carbohydrate-containing foods and drinks that necessitate emergency treatment. Because this behavior is secretive, her doctors wonder what they are doing wrong regarding her treatment. The patient herself seems very forgiving, tells them that she knows they are doing their best, and seems to enjoy the attention of doctors and nurses. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis for this case?","answers":[{"option":"Factitious disorder","bool":true},{"option":"Psychological factors affecting diabetes mellitus","bool":false},{"option":"Malingering","bool":false},{"option":"Somatoform disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Illness anxiety disorder","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 27-year-old electrical engineer is brought to the psychiatric unit involuntarily by his friend, who found a handwritten note in his apartment expressing feelings of hopelessness and despair, suggesting he might be contemplating ending his life. He recently lost his job and going through a crisis in his family. Which of the following is the most appropriate management step for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Give alternate plans for coping","bool":false},{"option":"Detain under mental health law","bool":true},{"option":"Assess the capacity of the patient","bool":false},{"option":"Involve significant others","bool":false},{"option":"Give him emergency numbers","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 25-month-old boy is brought to the outpatient department with complaints of being unable to walk. The father gave a history of delayed crying and was born with obstructed labor. On examination, he has increased tone and power of 2/5 in all four limbs. Which of the following is the most severe form of the above-mentioned disease?","answers":[{"option":"Spastic hemiplegia","bool":false},{"option":"Spastic quadriplegia","bool":true},{"option":"Spastic diplegia","bool":false},{"option":"Spastic paraplegia","bool":false},{"option":"Spastic monoplegia","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 3-year-old, partially vaccinated boy presented with acute onset of fever with inability to walk because of weakness in both feet. Weakness progressed over 2 days to involve the whole of both lower limbs. On examination, he was conscious but anxious and irritable. Vitals were normal. He had hypotonia, hyporeflexia, and power of grade 2/5 in both lower limbs with mute planters and intact sensations. Upper limbs and cranial nerves were intact. What would be the most appropriate test to confirm the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Stool for viral isolation 48 hours after the onset of weakness","bool":false},{"option":"Two stool samples, 24 to 48 hours apart for viral isolation","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) examination","bool":false},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) spine","bool":false},{"option":"Nerve conduction velocity (NCV)","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 2-year-old boy presented to the emergency room with a complaint of fever for 2 days and seizure for 30 minutes, 4 hours back. His temperature was 38°C. On examination, the throat was congested, and the central nervous system (CNS) examination was normal. What would be the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Epilepsy","bool":false},{"option":"Simple febrile seizure","bool":false},{"option":"Complex febrile seizure","bool":true},{"option":"Hypocalcemia","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 5-year-old boy was suffering from high-grade fever, cough, and runny nose for 3 days. Early in the morning, he developed right-sided focal fits involving the right arm, followed by unconsciousness for a few hours. Upon awakening, he was unable to move his right arm and right leg and had a left-sided facial palsy of the lower half. What would be the most likely cause of his condition?","answers":[{"option":"Left-sided infratentorial ischemic infarct","bool":true},{"option":"Right-sided cerebral ischemic infarct","bool":false},{"option":"Left-sided intra cerebral hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Left-sided cerebral ischemic infarct","bool":false},{"option":"Right-sided infratentorial hemorrhage","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 35-year-old clerk who lives in a slum area of Sindh, presented in the emergency department with low-grade fever, headache, and irritability for 2 months and one episode of uprolling of eyes, jerking of limbs, and incontinence of urine one day back. He had a history of chronic productive cough for six months. On examination, his Glasgow coma scale (GCS) score was 10/15 and he had bilateral papilledema. Which best possible treatment regimen would be appropriate to start?","answers":[{"option":"Anti-tuberculosis therapy, steroids, and analgesics","bool":false},{"option":"Antibiotics, steroids, and analgesics","bool":false},{"option":"Antifungal, analgesics, and anti-seizure drugs","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-tuberculosis therapy, steroids, and anti-seizure drugs","bool":true},{"option":"Antifungal, steroids and analgesics","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 70-year-old male patient presented to the neurology outpatient department with complaints of slowness of walking and abnormal movements of hands for two years. On examination, the attending physician noted bradykinesia, postural instability, and resting tremors in both hands. The tremors were more pronounced in the left hand. What is the typical frequency of tremors in this case?","answers":[{"option":"12 to 14 hertz","bool":false},{"option":"4 to 6 hertz","bool":true},{"option":"20 to 24 hertz","bool":false},{"option":"8 to 12 hertz","bool":false},{"option":"1 to 5 hertz","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 35-year-old female was referred to a tertiary care hospital with an hour history of sudden onset right-sided hemiplegia and aphasia. Her national institutes of health stroke scale (NIHSS) score was 20. The on-call neurologist was on board for consideration of an intravenous tissue plasminogen activator. He asked his junior to generate radiology requests immediately from the emergency department. Which specific imaging modality would be considered in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) brain and magnetic resonance venography (MRV)","bool":false},{"option":"Computed tomography (CT) scan brain plain","bool":true},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) brain and magnetic resonance angiogram (MRA)","bool":false},{"option":"Computed tomography (CT) scan brain with contrast","bool":false},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) brain plain","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 30-year-old male presented to the outpatient department with complaints of difficulty in climbing the stairs and holding heavy objects in her hands for 4 months. It was associated with significant weight loss, dry cough, and muscle pain for 6 months. On examination, he was pale and febrile with generalized wasting. Proximal muscle powers were 3/5 with intact reflexes and downgoing plantar. Sensory examination was normal. What would be most likely seen on his muscle biopsy?","answers":[{"option":"Peri-fascicular atrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Red ragged fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Type 2 muscle fiber atrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Endomysial inflammation","bool":true},{"option":"Necrotic muscle fibers","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 35-year-old male presented to the outpatient department with a complaint of sequential complete loss of vision in both eyes over one week. He had a history of both lower limb weakness 6 months back with minimal recovery despite taking treatment. On examination, he had no light perception in both eyes with bilateral pale disc. There was spastic quadriparesis with sensory level at the xiphisternum. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Paraneoplastic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Vasculitic infarctions","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Neuromyelitis optica","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin B12 deficiency","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 78-year-old otherwise healthy male is brought to the outpatient department with complaints of increasing forgetfulness, subtle behavioral changes, and difficulty in managing home finances for 6 months. On examination, he is vitally stable and his mini-mental state examination (MMSE) score is 22/30. All other neurological examinations are normal. Which of the following are the initial and most common presenting symptoms of the suspected illness?","answers":[{"option":"Dyspraxia","bool":false},{"option":"Episodic short term memory loss","bool":true},{"option":"Language dysfunction","bool":false},{"option":"Sleep disturbances","bool":false},{"option":"Incontinence","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 56-year-old female presented to the neurology outpatient department with complaints of multiple neurological symptoms that suddenly appeared two days ago. Her magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) brain showed an infarct in the left lateral medulla. Which of the following would most likely be present in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Right facial sensory loss","bool":false},{"option":"Left hemisensory loss","bool":false},{"option":"Dysphagia","bool":true},{"option":"Left hypoglossal nerve palsy","bool":false},{"option":"Hearing loss","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 52-year-old diabetic man presents to the emergency room with complaints of right-sided weakness and inability to speak for one hour. Acute stroke treatment is planned for him. What is the immediate target to save this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Penumbra","bool":true},{"option":"Core","bool":false},{"option":"Blocked artery","bool":false},{"option":"Unaffected cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Unaffected artery","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 27-year-old female presents to the emergency room with complaints of high-grade fever for one day and seizures for two hours. On examination, she has recurrent seizures, a fever of 103 degrees Fahrenheit, and a rigid neck. There is no focal weakness and both plantars are mute. Which of the following investigations has the highest diagnostic yield in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) brain","bool":false},{"option":"Computed tomography (CT) scan brain","bool":true},{"option":"Nasopharyngeal swab","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrospinal fluid studies","bool":false},{"option":"Blood culture","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 65-year-old gentleman presents to the outpatient department with complaints of twitching and wasting of his leg muscles for the last 2 years. He has also been experiencing progressive weakness in both lower limbs. He often chokes while drinking water and suddenly starts laughing without any reason. On examination, he has wasting and fasciculations in all four limbs with hyperreflexia and extensor plantar responses. What area of his nervous system is most likely affected?","answers":[{"option":"Dorsal spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal lobe of brain","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Motor neurons","bool":true},{"option":"Temporal lobe of brain","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"An 11-year-old male student is sent home from school because he daydreams in class and does not pay attention. During the clinical consultation, he becomes unresponsive for about 10-15 seconds. He stares blankly off into space and then suddenly resumes talking. He has no recollection that anything abnormal has happened. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Attention deficit hyperactivity disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Atonic seizures","bool":false},{"option":"Autism","bool":false},{"option":"Absence seizures","bool":true},{"option":"Dissociative disorder","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 30-year-old female presents to the emergency room. She is a known case of epilepsy and has been on no treatment for the last 2 weeks. She has generalized tonic-clonic seizures which are continuous for the last 30 minutes. On arrival in the emergency room, her oxygen saturation is 70% on room air. Seizures stop spontaneously but the patient does not regain consciousness. On examination, she is not opening her eyes even to painful stimuli. She is localizing a painful stimulus with both hands. She is making grunting noises at intervals. What is the Glasgow coma scale (GCS) score of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"6/15","bool":false},{"option":"12/15","bool":false},{"option":"15/15","bool":false},{"option":"3/15","bool":false},{"option":"7/15","bool":true}]},{"id":74,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 32-year-old male presents to the emergency department following a motor vehicle accident. On examination, there is a clear sensory level at the T6 dermatome on the left side of the body. Below this level, there is a loss of pain and temperature sensation on the left side and a loss of vibration and proprioception on the right side. Motor function is preserved on the right side but is impaired on the left side. What is the most likely\r\ndiagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior cord syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Cauda equina syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Conus medullaris syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal column syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Brown-sequard syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":75,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 20-year-old female presented with complaints of bilateral ptosis and fatigability for the last 2 years. After a clinical examination and confirmatory test, myasthenia gravis was diagnosed. Which of the following drugs would be safe to use?","answers":[{"option":"Ceftriaxone","bool":true},{"option":"Lithium","bool":false},{"option":"Chloroquine","bool":false},{"option":"Quinine","bool":false},{"option":"Procainamide","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A patient with Parkinson's disease presented at the rehabilitation medicine outpatient department for management. Which of the following statements is correct regarding rehabilitation management of Parkinson's disease?","answers":[{"option":"The psychologist will give therapy to improve the activity of daily living (ADLs)","bool":false},{"option":"There are no rehabilitation management options available for Parkinson's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Increased weighted utensils and adaptive equipment will improve the activities of daily living (ADLs)","bool":true},{"option":"Auditory and visual queuing increase the risk of fall","bool":false},{"option":"Exercise is harmful and increase the progress of disease","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 65-year-old male with a stroke presented to the rehabilitation outpatient department having left-sided hemiplegic and spastic gait. Which of the following orthosis is most commonly used to improve the gait of patients with stroke having spastic gait?","answers":[{"option":"Thoraco-lumbar orthosis (TLSO)","bool":false},{"option":"Supra-maleolar orthosis (SMO)","bool":false},{"option":"Ankle-foot orthosis (AFO)","bool":true},{"option":"Hip-knee-ankle-foot orthosis (HKAFO)","bool":false},{"option":"Knee-ankle-foot orthosis (KAFO)","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 44-year-old male presented to the outpatient department with complaints of ascending weakness in all four limbs for 5 days. He was operated on for lumbar disc herniation 3 weeks back and became ambulatory within a week. On examination, he had grade 2/5 power in all four limbs with diminished reflexes and downgoing plantar. Which of the following investigation findings is most likely to be present in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Increased serum creatine phosphokinase (CPK) levels","bool":false},{"option":"Elevated proteins in cerebrospinal fluid (CSF)","bool":true},{"option":"Spinal cord compression on imaging","bool":false},{"option":"Normal nerve conduction studies","bool":false},{"option":"Low serum potassium levels","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 6-year-old boy was brought to the outpatient department with complaints of frequent falls while running, and difficulty in rising from the ground. He had a positive family history of similar complaints. On examination, he was a young boy with an average build. Gait was lordotic. There was a scar mark over his right Achilles tendon. Powers were 4/5 in thigh muscles. Reflexes and sensations were normal. Which of the following is the most likely inheritance pattern of this disease?","answers":[{"option":"X-linked recessive","bool":true},{"option":"X-linked dominant","bool":false},{"option":"Maternal inheritance","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal recessive","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal dominant","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"An 18-year-old male presented with a history of frequent falls for the last two years. He had difficulty walking and due to imbalance became wheelchair-bound. He also had difficulty in carrying out daily household work describing a lack of precision. His family also noticed that his speech appeared to be drunken. He had no disturbance in memory and intellectual ability.  His sister also had a similar illness. On examination, he had dysarthric speech, truncal ataxia, and bilateral upgoing planters with absent ankle reflex. Regarding the above clinical scenario, what is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Autosomal dominant ataxia","bool":false},{"option":"Episodic ataxias","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B12 deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Friedreich's ataxia","bool":true},{"option":"Ataxia telangiectasia","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 50-year-old male presented with complaints of left-sided facial pain involving half-face only. The pain was aggravated with eating, chewing, and shaving. The pain was sharp, stabbing, sudden, and current-like. No associated complaints of hearing loss and tinnitus were reported. Neurological examination was unremarkable. What would be the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Chronic migraine","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Cluster headache","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal neuralgia","bool":true},{"option":"Myasthenia gravis","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A spinal cord injury patient having C6 American Spinal Injury Association (ASIA) impairment scale grade A, admitted to the ward suddenly complained of severe headache, flushing, dizziness, and disoriented. Her blood pressure was 160/100 mm Hg and her Foley catheter was clogged. What can be the most common diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Septic shock","bool":false},{"option":"Urinary tract infection","bool":false},{"option":"Acute myocardial infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Autonomic dysreflexia","bool":true},{"option":"Orthostatic hypotension","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"An 11-year-old girl presents with a history of increasing headaches upon awakening for the past month. On examination, papilledema is present bilaterally. A magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) of her brain reveals a 3-cm solid circumscribed mass within the fourth ventricle. There is a third and lateral cerebral ventricular dilatation. The mass is excised and microscopically shows perivascular pseudorosettes with round, regular tumor cells arranged around vessels. Which of the following neoplasms is she most likely to have?","answers":[{"option":"Glioblastoma","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytoma","bool":false},{"option":"Schwannoma","bool":false},{"option":"Medulloblastoma","bool":false},{"option":"Ependymoma","bool":true}]},{"id":84,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 10-year-old boy presents with a complaint of persistent headaches for the past 3 months. A computed tomography (CT) scan of the head shows a 4-centimeter cystic mass in the right cerebellar hemisphere. On gross examination, a cyst filled with gelatinous material. The cyst has a thin wall and a 1-centimeter mural nodule. Microscopically, the mass is composed of cells that have long, hair-like processes. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Medulloblastoma","bool":false},{"option":"Meningioma","bool":false},{"option":"Ependymoma","bool":false},{"option":"Hemangioblastoma","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytoma","bool":true}]},{"id":85,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 42-year-old male after a road traffic accident, suffered damage to the parietal lobe of his dominant hemisphere. What would be the most likely consequence?","answers":[{"option":"Unable to find defined places","bool":false},{"option":"Receptive aphasia","bool":false},{"option":"Denial of weakness (anosognosia)","bool":false},{"option":"Unable to appreciate three-dimensional sense","bool":true},{"option":"Neglect of contralateral limb","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 32-year-old man was brought to the emergency room because he had been stabbed in the back during a fight and was bleeding profusely. He was taken for emergency surgery in the operating room. The surgeon realized that this patient had suffered a right lateral hemi-section of the spinal cord, at the level of C8, due to a stab wound. A brief physical examination of the patient was conducted when he arrived in the emergency room. What findings were most likely present in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Flaccid paralysis of the right lower limb","bool":false},{"option":"Spastic paralysis of the right lower limb","bool":true},{"option":"Spastic paralysis of the left upper limb","bool":false},{"option":"Spastic paralysis of the right lower face","bool":false},{"option":"Spastic paralysis of the left lower limb","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A neurologist while examining a 48-year-old patient noticed that he had lost the ability to discriminate between two points presented simultaneously on the skin of the left hand.\r\nAnatomically what is the most likely site of the lesion?","answers":[{"option":"Fasciculus gracilis on the right side of the medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Fasciculus cuneatus on the right side of the spinal cord at C2","bool":false},{"option":"The spinothalamic tract on the left side of the spinal cord at C2","bool":false},{"option":"Medial lemniscus on the right side of the pons","bool":true},{"option":"Dorsal column on the right side of the spinal cord at T5","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 39-year-old HIV-positive man has received no antiretroviral therapy. A computed tomography (CT) scan of the head shows no intracranial hemorrhage, but there is a midline shift. A magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) of the brain shows a 4-centimeter circumscribed and solid mass. Cytologic examination shows large cells with large nuclei and scant cytoplasm that are marked with CD20, but not with glial fibrillary acidic protein (GFAP) or cytokeratin. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Kaposi sarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Medulloblastoma","bool":false},{"option":"Large B-cell lymphoma","bool":true},{"option":"Glioblastoma","bool":false},{"option":"Progressive multifocal leukoencephalopathy","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 58-year-old man was brought to the emergency room by his wife, as he developed difficulty in speaking and weakness in his right upper limb. However, he was able to understand what was being said to him. His symptoms began around 1 hour ago. His previous medical history was significant for hypertension for the past 18 years. After doing a physical examination on the patient, the doctor ordered a computed tomography (CT) scan of the head as his provisional diagnosis was that of stroke. Which vessel is most likely to be occluded in the patient?","answers":[{"option":"Left middle cerebral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Left superior cerebellar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Left anterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Right middle cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Right anterior cerebral artery","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Closed head injury resulting from an accident or cerebrovascular disease causing a stroke in the specific lobe of the brain may result in disruptions to social and emotional behavior. This can be produced by damage to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Paracentral lobule","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal lobe","bool":true},{"option":"Temporal lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Occipital lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal lobe","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following is an intravenous induction agent?","answers":[{"option":"Nalbuphine","bool":false},{"option":"Lignocaine","bool":false},{"option":"Propofol","bool":true},{"option":"Atracurium","bool":false},{"option":"Fentanyl","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following intravenous induction agents cause pain during administration?","answers":[{"option":"Propofol","bool":true},{"option":"Ketamine","bool":false},{"option":"Atracurium","bool":false},{"option":"Diazepam","bool":false},{"option":"Fentanyl","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following is an ultra-short-acting opioid?","answers":[{"option":"Fentanyl","bool":false},{"option":"Remifentanil","bool":true},{"option":"Nalbuphine","bool":false},{"option":"Tramal","bool":false},{"option":"Pethidine","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"What are the structures that get pierced during spinal anesthesia?","answers":[{"option":"Ligament, ligamentum flavum, and dura mater","bool":false},{"option":"Skin, subcutaneous tissue, supraspinous ligament, interspinous ligament, ligamentum flavum, and dura mater","bool":true},{"option":"Skin, subcutaneous tissue, supraspinous ligament, interspinous ligament, and ligamentum flavum","bool":false},{"option":"Skin, superficial fascia, and supraspinous muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Supraspinous ligament, interspinous ligament, ligamentum flavum, and dura mater","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"In adults, the spinal cord extends to which of the following levels?","answers":[{"option":"S2","bool":false},{"option":"L3","bool":false},{"option":"L2","bool":false},{"option":"L1","bool":true},{"option":"L5","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"While transferring a patient through an air ambulance which of the following occurs due to high altitude?","answers":[{"option":"High blood pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Increased pulse","bool":false},{"option":"Increased systemic vascular resistance (SVR)","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoxia","bool":true},{"option":"Low air in an endotracheal tube (ETT) cuff","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"According to the World Health Organization (WHO) pain relief ladder, moderate to severe pain should be treated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Acetaminophen","bool":false},{"option":"Nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs)","bool":false},{"option":"Counselling","bool":false},{"option":"Acupuncture","bool":false},{"option":"Opioids ± adjuvant","bool":true}]},{"id":98,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"An unpleasant sensory and emotional experience associated with or potential in terms of such damage is defined as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Delirium","bool":false},{"option":"Depression","bool":false},{"option":"Behavior disturbance","bool":false},{"option":"Anxiety","bool":false},{"option":"Pain","bool":true}]},{"id":99,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 25-year-old female planned for elective cesarian section. The patient is planned to proceed in central neuraxial blockade. It includes which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Spinal","bool":false},{"option":"Single nerve block","bool":false},{"option":"Infiltration","bool":false},{"option":"Topical anesthetics","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal + epidural","bool":true}]},{"id":100,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 10-year-old boy is brought to the emergency room by his parents. He has been complaining of headache, fever, and stiff neck for the past 2 days. He is also vomiting and has had no appetite. On physical examination, he is found to be febrile (102°F) and Kerning's sign is present. The rest of the examination is unremarkable. His computed tomography (CT) scan of the brain is normal. What investigation will be appropriate to perform to reach a diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) brain with contrast","bool":false},{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray skull and paranasal sinuses","bool":false},{"option":"C-reactive protein","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) studies","bool":true}]},{"id":101,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 45-year-old man, a known case of diabetes with good glycemic control, was referred to the emergency room with a diagnosis of ischemic stroke. He developed weakness in his left upper and lower limbs 2 hours ago. His blood pressure was 130/80 mmHg and his blood sugar was normal. His computed tomography (CT) scan of the brain showed a right frontal infarct. He had no significant history. All laboratory investigations were normal. What would be the best treatment for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Aspirin and clopidogrel","bool":false},{"option":"Tissue plasminogen activator (tpa) infusion","bool":true},{"option":"Heparin infusion","bool":false},{"option":"Clopidogrel","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":false}]},{"id":102,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A young man is brought to the emergency room with a severe sudden headache within 2 hours after the onset. Which finding should be looked for in plain computed tomography (CT) brain?","answers":[{"option":"High density in cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) spaces","bool":true},{"option":"Low density in basal ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"High density in basal ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Mixed high and low density in subcortical white matter","bool":false},{"option":"Low density in white matter","bool":false}]},{"id":103,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"When prescribing clozapine, which side effect is the most feared and should be closely monitored?","answers":[{"option":"Sedation","bool":false},{"option":"Agranulocytosis","bool":true},{"option":"Weight gain","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperglycemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypotension","bool":false}]},{"id":104,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"What is the most common side effect associated with sumatriptan?","answers":[{"option":"Coronary vasospasm","bool":true},{"option":"Precipitation of seizures","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac arrhythmia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Precipitation of psychosis","bool":false}]},{"id":105,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following acts as an inverse agonist of the benzodiazepine receptor?","answers":[{"option":"Lorazepam","bool":false},{"option":"Beta carboline","bool":true},{"option":"Flumazenil","bool":false},{"option":"Diazepam","bool":false},{"option":"Alprazolam","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"What is the recommended medication for the management of acute opioid poisoning?","answers":[{"option":"Naloxone","bool":true},{"option":"Diazepam","bool":false},{"option":"Acetaminophen","bool":false},{"option":"Diphenhydramine","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which psychoactive alkaloid is primarily responsible for the effects of marijuana?","answers":[{"option":"Caffeine","bool":false},{"option":"Cannabidiol (CBD)","bool":false},{"option":"Morphine","bool":false},{"option":"Tetrahydrocannabinol (THC)","bool":true},{"option":"Nicotine","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which finding on clinical examination would confirm the diagnosis of transverse myelitis?","answers":[{"option":"Loss of proprioception below a particular level","bool":false},{"option":"Muscle weakness on one side of the body","bool":false},{"option":"Inability to grasp objects","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of all sensation below a certain level","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased tactile sensation in a defined area","bool":false}]},{"id":109,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 30-year-old female presents to the clinic with a sudden onset loss of vision, weakness, and paraparesis. A diagnosis was made of neuromyelitis optica affecting the dorsal columns, what would be observed on spinal MRI?","answers":[{"option":"Periventricular changes","bool":false},{"option":"Longitudinally extensive transverse myelitis","bool":true},{"option":"T-cell mediated immune response","bool":false},{"option":"Patchy changes in 1 to 2 spinal segments","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal cord tenderness","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A child presents to the clinic with fever and left leg paralysis. What is the appropriate investigation?","answers":[{"option":"Electroencephalogram (EEG) for seizure activity","bool":false},{"option":"Blood culture","bool":false},{"option":"Stool viral antigen test","bool":true},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrospinal fluid analysis","bool":false}]},{"id":111,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"In a patient with a spinal cord injury at or above the T6 level presenting with hypertension in the upper body, what is the underlying cause of this phenomenon?","answers":[{"option":"Baroreceptor dysfunction","bool":false},{"option":"Renal artery stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Somatic denervation","bool":false},{"option":"Parasympathetic activation","bool":false},{"option":"Autonomic dysfunction","bool":true}]},{"id":112,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A patient presents with symptoms suggestive of raised intracranial pressure (ICP), what triad of clinical manifestations is typically observed?","answers":[{"option":"Diplopia, ptosis, ophthalmoplegia","bool":false},{"option":"Headache, vomiting, papilledema","bool":true},{"option":"Seizures, focal neurological deficits, confusion","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension, bradycardia, urinary incontinence","bool":false},{"option":"Fever, neck stiffness, altered mental status","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"What is the most common complication observed during rehabilitation in post-stroke patients due to faulty positioning?","answers":[{"option":"Contractures","bool":false},{"option":"Muscle spasms","bool":false},{"option":"Pressure ulcers","bool":true},{"option":"Swallowing problems","bool":false},{"option":"Bladder incontinence","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 50-year-old farmer has been exhibiting agitated behavior for the past few weeks. He appears restless, irritable and increasingly withdrawn from his usual activities. Over the last day, he has refused to eat or drink anything and has shown resistance to going outside for fresh air, despite previously enjoying spending time outdoors. Additionally, he has developed some motor symptoms including muscle spasms. Based on the clinical presentation described, what is the likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Delirium","bool":false},{"option":"Tetanus","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculous meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Rabies encephalitis","bool":true},{"option":"Acute bacterial meningitis","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 32-year-old patient presents with recurrent seizures. On examination, there are no signs of meningeal irritation, and the patient's blood sugar level is within normal limits at 90 mg/dl. Imaging studies reveal abnormal findings in both temporal lobes. What is the most appropriate management for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"IV steroids","bool":false},{"option":"IV ceftriaxone","bool":false},{"option":"IV phenytoin","bool":false},{"option":"Supportive care with hydration and monitoring","bool":false},{"option":"IV acyclovir","bool":true}]},{"id":116,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A middle-aged male presents with a diffuse headache that has persisted for a few weeks. The headache has a gradual onset and is associated with weight loss, anorexia, and pain on jaw movement. Upon fundoscopy, the only finding noted is a pale optic disc. How can a definite diagnosis be reached in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Erythrocyte sedimentation rate","bool":false},{"option":"Lumbar puncture","bool":false},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging","bool":false},{"option":"Computed tomography","bool":false},{"option":"Biopsy of temporal arteries","bool":true}]},{"id":117,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A patient presents with ataxia along with a rash observed on the earlobes and conjunctiva. What is the likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Wilson disease","bool":false},{"option":"Friedreich ataxia","bool":false},{"option":"Guillain-Barré syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Ataxia telangiectasia","bool":true},{"option":"Multiple sclerosis","bool":false}]},{"id":118,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"What type of meningioma is characterized by a whorled continuous pattern of cells with psammoma calcifications, without distinct cell membranes?","answers":[{"option":"Atypical meningioma","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrocystic meningioma","bool":false},{"option":"Anaplastic meningioma","bool":false},{"option":"Transitional meningioma","bool":false},{"option":"Syncytial meningioma","bool":true}]},{"id":119,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"What is the most common cause of bacterial meningitis in a 22-year-old male?","answers":[{"option":"Hemophilus influenzae","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Listeria monocytogenes","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria meningitidis","bool":true}]},{"id":120,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A young child exhibits difficulty walking, spasticity in all four limbs, poor feeding, and delayed milestones. Which condition is most likely indicated?","answers":[{"option":"Down syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Autism spectrum disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral palsy","bool":true},{"option":"Guillain-Barré syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Muscular dystrophy","bool":false}]},{"id":121,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"An 18-year-old male with a history of delayed milestones and anoxia during birth exhibits difficulty walking properly. Which condition is most likely indicated?","answers":[{"option":"Spina bifida","bool":false},{"option":"Parkinson disease","bool":false},{"option":"Muscular dystrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Down syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral palsy","bool":true}]},{"id":122,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 5-year-old child presents to the outpatient department with loss of consciousness and a history of recurrent tonic-clonic convulsions over the past year. Birth and development were reported as normal. What is the likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Syncope","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral palsy","bool":false},{"option":"Epilepsy","bool":true},{"option":"Stroke","bool":false},{"option":"Complex febrile convulsions","bool":false}]},{"id":123,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A child is brought unconscious to the emergency room with a history of seizures. The seizures started with twisting of the neck and eye deviation to one side, then progressing to jerky movements of all four limbs of the body. What is the true categorization of this seizure?","answers":[{"option":"Focal onset with impaired awareness","bool":false},{"option":"Generalized tonic-clonic","bool":false},{"option":"Focal progressing to bilateral tonic-clonic","bool":true},{"option":"Generalized myoclonic","bool":false},{"option":"Generalized non-myoclonic","bool":false}]},{"id":124,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following is the safest approach for brachial block?","answers":[{"option":"Interscalene","bool":false},{"option":"Axillary","bool":false},{"option":"Infraclavicular","bool":true},{"option":"Combined ulnar median radial","bool":false},{"option":"Supraclavicular","bool":false}]},{"id":125,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A hypertensive patient presents with a stroke while being treated for a disease. His blood pressure is 180/105 mmHg, the platelet count is 85,000/mm³, fever is 101°F, PT/INR is 1.6, and dengue NS1 antigen is positive. What represents an absolute contraindication to tissue plasminogen activator (tPA) administration?","answers":[{"option":"Fever 101°F","bool":false},{"option":"Positive dengue serology","bool":false},{"option":"PT/INR 1.6","bool":false},{"option":"BP >180/105 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"Platelets 85000/mm³","bool":true}]},{"id":126,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"Which of the following drugs is used for dissociative anesthesia?","answers":[{"option":"Ketamine","bool":true},{"option":"Propofol","bool":false},{"option":"Thiopental","bool":false},{"option":"Midazolam","bool":false},{"option":"Sevoflurane","bool":false}]},{"id":127,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A child is scheduled for an ENT surgery. Which potent local anesthetic with intrinsic vasoconstrictive effects is considered?","answers":[{"option":"Lidocaine","bool":false},{"option":"Tetracaine","bool":false},{"option":"Procaine","bool":false},{"option":"Cocaine","bool":true},{"option":"Bupivacaine","bool":false}]},{"id":128,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A student enters variables into the SPSS software, such as marital status and groups like medicine used/placebo. What type of variables are these?","answers":[{"option":"Numerical","bool":false},{"option":"Scale","bool":false},{"option":"Nominal","bool":true},{"option":"Ordinal","bool":false},{"option":"Scientific notation","bool":false}]},{"id":129,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"What contributes significantly to the global burden of neurological disease?","answers":[{"option":"Alzheimer disease and other dementias","bool":false},{"option":"Parkinson disease","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrovascular diseases","bool":true},{"option":"Migraine","bool":false},{"option":"Epilepsy","bool":false}]},{"id":130,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"More than half of the neurological burden in disability-adjusted life years (DALYs) is attributed to which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Epilepsy","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrovascular diseases","bool":true},{"option":"Migraine","bool":false},{"option":"Alzheimer disease and other dementias","bool":false},{"option":"Parkinson disease","bool":false}]},{"id":131,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A 45-year-old female patient who is a known case of an autoimmune disorder visits the neurology clinic with complaints of fatigue, tingling, numbness, muscle weakness, and muscle spasms. CSF analysis reveals oligoclonal bands. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Perivascular lymphocytes and demyelination of white matter","bool":true},{"option":"Lewy bodies in substantia nigra","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of Purkinje cells in the cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Spongiform changes in the cerebral cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Tau protein aggregates in neurofibrillary tangles","bool":false}]},{"id":132,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"A woman who has been on medication for risk factors of ischemic heart disease (IHD) experiences leg cramps. She recently started treatment for secondary control of hypertension, but she subsequently developed pain in her limbs. Her creatine kinase (CKP) levels have risen to 10 times normal. Which drug has she been taking?","answers":[{"option":"Beta-blockers","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":false},{"option":"Angiotensin-converting enzyme (ACE) inhibitors","bool":false},{"option":"Statins","bool":true},{"option":"Digoxin","bool":false}]},{"id":133,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2023","question":"What is the recommended treatment for Guillain-Barré syndrome (GBS)?","answers":[{"option":"High dose corticosteroids","bool":false},{"option":"IV immunoglobulin","bool":true},{"option":"Interferon beta","bool":false},{"option":"Endotracheal intubation","bool":false},{"option":"IV acyclovir","bool":false}]}]
export default arr